Guide to the Robert A. Caro Archive [DATE]–2021 MS 3203
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York (published 1974), [1966–1973?]
  - Subseries III.G. Power Broker drafts, undated
    - Power Broker draft. "Book One / Wait Until the Evening," pp. 1-127 (Box P18, Folder #)
      Copy of previous version.
    - Power Broker draft. "Book One / Wait Until the Evening," pp. 1-127 (Box P18, Folder #)
      Copy of previous version, with additional handwritten corrections.
      Includes tentative title page: "THE POWER BROKER / The Story of Robert Moses, His Forty-Four Years of Power And Their Effect on New York City and the Urban Policies of America."
    - Power Broker draft. Mss 553-1020 [3 folders] (Box P18, Folder 5-7)
    - Power Broker draft. Mss 1021-1312 [2 folders] (Box P18, Folder 8-9)
    - Power Broker draft. Mss 1313-1708 [3 folders] (Box P18, Folder 10-12)
    - Power Broker draft. Mss 1709-1955 [2 folders] (Box P20, Folder 1-2)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1 to 120 (Box P20, Folder 3)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 21 (Box P20, Folder 4)
    - Power Broker draft, Chapter ??, pp. 866 to 891 (Box P20, Folder 5)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 870 to 941 [stamped 708 to 780] (Box P20, Folder 6)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 23, pp. 1000 to 1047g (version 1) (Box P20, Folder 7)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 23, pp. 1000 to 1047g (version 2) (Box P20, Folder 8)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 24, pp. 1048 to 1081g (version 1) (Box P20, Folder 9)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 24, pp. 1051 to 1081g (version 2) (Box P20, Folder 10)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 25, pp. 1082 to 1174 (Box P20, Folder 11)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 26, pp. 1215 to 1312 (Box P20, Folder 12)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1371 to 1397 (Box P20, Folder 13)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 27 (changed from 26), pp. 1398 to 1467 (Box P20, Folder 14)
      Includes typed note from Caro to Bob Gottlieb, April 9, 1973, discussing proposed cuts which Caro felt would alter the book to the point where it would no longer resemble the one he wanted to write.
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1503 to 1525 (Box P20, Folder 15)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1600 to 1668 (Box P20, Folder 16)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1745 to 1800 (Box P20, Folder 17)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1826 to 1875 (Box P20, Folder 18)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 30, pp. 1876 to 1895 (Box P20, Folder 19)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 1946 to 2059 (Box P20, Folder 20)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 33, pp. 2060 to 2091 (Box P20, Folder 21)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 35, pp. 2250 to 2276 (Box P20, Folder 22)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 36, pp. 2300 to 2311 (Box P20, Folder 23)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 37, pp. 2312 to 2356 (Box P20, Folder 24)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 2625, 2625a, 2625b (Box P20, Folder 25)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 45 (changed from 43), pp. 2852 to 2900 (Box P20, Folder 26)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 46 (changed from 44), pp. 2900 to 2978 (Box P20, Folder 27)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 3002 to 3019 (Box P20, Folder 28)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [29], pp. 29-5 to 29-13 (Box P20, Folder 29)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 33, p.33-1 (Box P20, Folder 30)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [37], pp. 37-10 to 37-56 (Box P20, Folder 31)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [38], pp. 38-24 to 38-56 (Box P20, Folder 32)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [47], pp. 47-21 (Box P20, Folder 33)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 49 (changed from 47), pp. 47-2 to 47-79 (Box P20, Folder 34)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [48], pp. 48-14 to 48-22 (Box P20, Folder 35)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [49], pp. 49-30 to 49-37 (Box P20, Folder 36)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [50], pp. 50-22 to 50-40 (Box P20, Folder 37)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 51, pp. 51-1 to 51-29 (Box P20, Folder 38)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 52, pp. 52-1 to 52-18 (Box P20, Folder 39)
    - Power Broker draft. Miscellaneous (Box P20, Folder 40)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 761 to 788 (Box P22, Folder 1)
      Typed draft of PowerBroker, with edits. Galley of LBJ Vol 1.
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, stamped pages 1 to 174 (Box P22, Folder 2)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, stamped pages 175 to 341 (Box P22, Folder 3)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, stamped pages 342 to 538 (Box P22, Folder 4)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, stamped pages 539 to 711 (Box P22, Folder 5)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, stamped pages 712 to 863 (Box P22, Folder 6)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 44, pp. 2800 to 2850 (Box P24, Folder 1)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 42, pp. 41-1 to 41-19, stamped 1707 to 1725 (Box P24, Folder 2)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 31, pp. 1896 to 1945 (Box P24, Folder 3)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 2572RR to 2572ZZ (Box P24, Folder 4)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 652VVV to 652OOOO (Box P24, Folder 5)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 38, pp. 2573 to 2573Y (Box P24, Folder 6)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 41, pp. 2700 to 2725jj (Box P24, Folder 7)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter [42], pp. 42-33 to 42-46 (Box P24, Folder 8)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 43, pp. 2725 to 2784 (Box P24, Folder 9)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter ??, pp. 2357 to 2574 [2 folders] (Box P24, Folder 10-11)
    - Power Broker draft. Chapter 37, pp. 2572a to 2572qq (Box P24, Folder 12)
  - Subseries III.H. Power Broker galleys, [circa 1973-1974]
    Galleys or galley proofs—so-called after the tray, or galley, that held printers' type—are preliminary or trial sheets of text, often produced in long, continuous strips, printed for the checking of typographical or other errors. Shared among a work's author, editor, and printer, they bear deletions, additions, and other emendations made to the text before final publication. These galleys of The Power Broker show considerable changes by Caro and others (one set is marked "Gottlieb's," indicating it was the copy of Caro's editor, Robert Gottlieb), often in the form of pencil cross-outs and manuscript additions, but also frequently as stapled-on passages or instructive notes to the printer.
    The galleys are presented in the order in which the archivist encountered them. None of the sets appears complete. Chapter numbers, titles, and bank and slide ranges (i.e., the numbering system used in production of the sheets) are listed to enable the researcher to locate desired sections of the book.
    - Power Broker galley proof: Chapters 1-45, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P16, Identifier left side)
      Top page circled in red "Gottlieb's."
      Introduction, "Wait Until the Evening" [Bank 1, Slides 1-9]
      Chapter 1, "Line of Succession" [Bank 1, Slides 10-15]
      Chapter 2, "Robert Moses at Yale" [Bank 1, Slides 16-19]
      Chapter 3, "Home Away from Home" [Bank 1, Slides 20-23]
      Chapter 4, "Burning" [Bank 1, Slides 24-28]
      Chapter 5, "Age of Optimism" [Bank 1, Slides 29-35]
      Chapter 6, "Curriculum Changes" [Bank 1, Slides 36-45]
      Chapter 7, "Change in Major" [Bank 1, Slides 45-54]
      Chapter 8, "The Taste of Power" [Bank 1, Slides 55-57]
      Chapter 9, "A Dream" [Bank 1, Slides 58-68]
      Chapter 10, "The Best Bill Drafter in Albany" [Bank 1, Slides 69-71]
      Chapter 11, "The Majesty of the Law" [Bank 1, Slides 72-82]
      Chapter 12, "Robert Moses and the Creature of the Machine" [Bank 1, Slides 83-90]
      Chapter 13, "Driving" [Bank 1, Slides 91-96]
      Chapter 14, "Changing" [Bank 1, Slides 97-104]
      Chapter 15, "Curator of Cauliflowers" [Bank 1, Slides 105-113]
      Chapter 16, "The Featherduster" [Bank 1, Slides 114-120]
      Chapter 17, "The Mother of Accommodation" [Bank 1, Slides 120-128]
      Chapter 18, "New York City Before Robert Moses" [Bank 1, Slides 129-138]
      Chapter 19, "To Power in the City" [Bank 1, Slides 139-146]
      Chapter 20, "One Year" [Bank 1, Slides 147-150; Bank 2, Slides 1-10]
      Chapter 21, "The Candidate" [Bank 2, Slides 10-19]
      Chapter 22, "Order Number 129" [Bank 2, Slides 20-27]
      Chapter 23, "In the Saddle" [Bank 2, Slides 27-36]
      Chapter 24, "Driving" [Bank 2, Slides 37-48]
      Chapter 25, "Changing" [Bank 2, Slides 49-82]
      Chapter 26, "Brother, Husband, Father, Friend" (published as "Two Brothers") [Bank 2, Slides 82-94]
      Chapter 27, "Changing" [Bank 2, Slides 94-97]
      Chapter 28, "The Warp on the Loom" [Bank 2, Slides 98-106]
      Chapter 29, "And When the Devil Turns.. ." (published as "And When the Last Law Was Down.. .") [Bank 2, Slides 107-123]
      Chapter 30, "Revenge" [Bank 2, Slides 123-127]
      Chapter 31, "Monopoly" [Bank 2, Slides 128-131]
      Chapter 32, "Quid Pro Quo" (incomplete) [Bank 2, Slide 132]
      Chapter 33, "Leading Out the Regiment" (incomplete) [Bank 3, Slides 1-5]
      Chapter 34, "Moses and the Mayors" [Bank 3, Slides 5-26]
      Chapter 35, "RM" [Bank 3, Slides 26-39]
      Chapter 36, "The Meat Ax" [Bank 3, Slides 40-45]
      Chapter 37, "One Mile" [Bank 3, Slides 45-58]
      Chapter 38, "One Mile (Afterward)" (incomplete) [Bank 3, Slides 59, 62]
      Chapter 39, "The Highwayman" [Bank 3, Slides 63-73]
      Chapter 40, "Point of No Return" [Bank 3, Slides 73-90]
      Chapter 41, "Rumors and the Report of Rumors" [Bank 3, Slides 91-100]
      Chapter 42, "Tavern in the Town" [Bank 3, Slides 101-109]
      Chapter 43, "Late Arrival" [Bank 3, Slides 109-117]
      Chapter 44, "Mustache and the Bard" [Bank 3, Slides 118-123]
      Chapter 45, "Off to the Fair" (incomplete) [Bank 3, Slides 123-129]
    - Power Broker galley proof: Chapters 21-50, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P16, Identifier right side)
      Chapter 32, "Quid Pro Quo" [Bank 2, Slides 132-133]
      Chapter 33, "Leading Out the Regiment" [Bank 2, Slides 134-150; Bank 3, Slides 1-5]
      Chapter 38, "One Mile (Afterward)" [Bank 3, Slides 59-62]
      Chapter 42, "Tavern in the Town" (incomplete) [Bank 3, Slides 101-108]
      Chapter 46, "Nelson" (incomplete) [Bank 3, Slides 135-140]
      Chapter 47, "The Great Fair" [Bank 3, Slides 141-150; Bank 17, Slides 1-4]
      Chapter 48, "Old Lion" (published as "Old Lion, Young Mayor") [Bank 17, Slides 5-10]
      Chapter 49, "The Last Stand" [Bank 17, Slides 11-16]
      Chapter 50, "Old" [Bank 17, Slides 16-22]
    - Power Broker galley proof: Chapters 18-50, Notes, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P19, Identifier left side)
      Chapter 20, "One Year" [Bank 1, Slide 147 through Bank 2, Slide 10]
      Chapter 26, "Brother, Husband, Father, Friend" (published as "Two Brothers") [Bank 2, Slides 82-93]
      Chapter 33, "Leading Out the Regiment" [Bank 2, Slide 134, through Bank 3, Slide 5]
      Chapter 42, "Tavern in the Tow" [Bank 3, Slides 101-109]
      Chapter 45, "Off to the Fair" [Bank 3, Slides 123-134]
      Chapter 46, "Nelson" [Bank 3, Slides 134-140]
      Notes [Bank 17, Slides 23-84]
    - Power Broker galley proof: Introduction, Chapters 1-50, Notes, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P19, Identifier right side)
      Introduction, "Wait Until the Evening" [Bank 83, Slides 8-18]
      Chapter 1, "Line of Succession" [Bank 83, Slides 19-25]
      Chapter 2, "Robert Moses at Yale" [Bank 83, Slides 26-30]
      Chapter 3, "Home Away from Home" [Bank 83, Slides 31-34]
      Chapter 4, "Burning" [Bank 83, Slides 35-41]
      Chapter 5, "Age of Optimism" [Bank 83, Slides 41-50]
      Chapter 6, "Curriculum Changes" [Bank 83, Slides 51-62]
      Chapter 7, "Change in Major" [Bank 83, Slides 62-73]
      Chapter 8, "The Taste of Power" [Bank 83, Slides 74-77]
      Chapter 9, "A Dream" [Bank 83, Slides 77-91]
      Chapter 10, "The Best Bill Drafter in Albany" [Bank 83, Slides 92-94]
      Chapter 11, "The Majesty of the Law" [Bank 83, Slides 95-108]
      Chapter 12, "Robert Moses and the Creature of the Machine" [Bank 83, Slides 108-117]
      Chapter 13, "Driving" [Bank 83, Slides 118-125]
      Chapter 14, "Changing" [Bank 83, Slides 125-134]
      Chapter 15, "Curator of Cauliflowers" [Bank 83, Slides 135-146]
      Chapter 16, "The Featherduster" [Bank 83, Slides 146-150; Bank 84, Slides 1-4]
      Chapter 17, "The Mother of Accommodation" [Bank 84, Slides 4-16]
      Chapter 18, "New York City Before Robert Moses" [Bank 84, Slides 16-18, 29]
      Chapter 19, "To Power in the City" [Bank 84, Slides 29-34]
      Chapter 17, "The Mother of Accommodation" [Bank 84, Slides 4-16 (incomplete)]
      Chapter 18, "New York City Before Robert Moses" [Bank 84, Slides 16-29 (incomplete)]
      Chapter 19, "To Power in the City" [Bank 84, Slides 29-39]
      Chapter 20, "One Year" [Bank 84, Slides 40-56]
      Chapter 21, "The Candidate" [Bank 84, Slides 59-70]
      Chapter 22, "Order Number 129" [Bank 84, Slides 71-79]
      Chapter 23, "In the Saddle" [Bank 84, Slides 80-91]
      Chapter 24, "Driving" [Bank 84, Slides 92-106]
      Chapter 25, "Changing" [Bank 84, Slides 107-145]
      Chapter 26, "Brother, Husband, Father, Friend" (published as "Two Brothers") [Bank 84, Slides 146-150; Bank 88, Slides 1-11]
      Chapter 27, "Changing" [Bank 88, Slides 11-15]
      Chapter 28, "The Warp on the Loom" [Bank 88, Slides 15-26]
      Chapter 29, "And When the Last Law Was Down.. ." [Bank 88, Slides 27-50]
      Chapter 30, "Revenge" [Bank 88, Slides 51-57]
      Chapter 31, "Monopoly" [Bank 88, Slides 57-62]
      Chapter 32, "Quid Pro Quo" [Bank 88, Slides 62-64]
      Chapter 33, "Leading Out the Regiment" [Bank 88, Slides 64-90]
      Chapter 34, "Moses and the Mayors" [Bank 88, Slides 90-116]
      Chapter 35, "RM" [Bank 88, Slides 116-132]
      Chapter 36, "The Meat Ax" [Bank 88, Slides 132-139]
      Chapter 37, "One Mile" [Bank 88, Slides 140-149; Bank 95, Slides 1-8]
      Chapter 38, "One Mile (Afterward)" [Bank 95, Slides 8-13]
      Chapter 39, "The Highwayman" [Bank 95, Slides 13-25]
      Chapter 40, "Point of No Return" [Bank 95, Slides 26-46]
      Chapter 41, "Rumors and the Report of Rumors" [Bank 95, Slides 47-58]
      Chapter 42, "Tavern in the Town" [Bank 95, Slides 59-69]
      Chapter 43, "Late Arrival" [Bank 95, Slides 69-79]
      Chapter 44, "Mustache and the Bard" [Bank 95, Slides 80-86]
      Chapter 45, "Off to the Fair" [Bank 95, Slides 87-100]
      Chapter 46, "Nelson" [Bank 95, Slide 100; Bank 128, Slides 4-10]
      Chapter 47, "The Great Fair" [Bank 128, Slides 11-28]
      Chapter 48, "Old Lion, Young Mayor" [Bank 128, Slides 28-36]
      Chapter 49, "The Last Stand" [Bank 128, Slides 38-44]
      Chapter 50, "Old" [Bank 128, Slides 44-53]
      Debts [Bank 34, Slide 160]
      Notes [Bank 17, Slides 22-62]
    - Power Broker galley proof: Introduction, Chapters 1-20, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P24, Identifier left side)
    - Power Broker galley proof: Chapters 21-23, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P24, Identifier right side)
      Cahpter 22, "Order Number 129" [Bank 84, Slides 71-79]
      Chapter 23, "In the Saddle" [Bank 84, Slides 80-81]
    - Power Broker galley proof: Chapters 1-17, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P73, Identifier left side)
      Chapter 9, "A Dream" [Bank 1, Slides 58-??]
      Chapter 10, "The Best Bill Drafter in Albany" [Bank 1, Slides ??-71]
    - Power Broker galley proof: Index, Dedication, Table of Contents, Illustration Captions, Photo Credits, [circa 1973-1974] (Box P73, Identifier right side)
      Index [Bank 45, Slides 60-77]
      Index [Bank 45, Slides 60-89]
      Dedication & Table of Contents [Bank 69, Slides 53-54]
      Illustration Captions
      Photo Credits
  - Subseries III.I. Power Broker promotional material, [DATE-DATE]
  - Subseries III.J. Power Broker oversize material and objects, [DATE-DATE]
    Framed items and large objects and promotional materials.
    The items are listed chronologically.
    - Framed photograph (12x10) of Robert Moses, Fiorello La Guardia, and Al Smith judging a barber shop quartet singing contest, 1940 (Object 09)
    - Power Broker research filing cabinet, [1966–1973?] (Object 01)
      See Series III for former contents.
    - Joe McGarrity. Original cover art for Times Advertiser supplement "this week", 1974 (Object 06)
      Acrylic, ink, and graphite on paper image of Robert and Ina Caro, Robert Moses, with the cover of "The Power Broker."
    - Framed New York Post article (19x14) re: Power Broker, 1974 (Object 10)
    - Framed publicity ad (25x15) for Power Broker, [1974] (Object 13)
    - Framed photograph (12x10) of Caro holding a copy of Robert Massie's "Peter the Great" and Massie holding Caro's "The Power Broker," with their mutual editor, Robert Gottlieb, between them, after 1980 (Object 08)
- Series IV. The Years of Lyndon Johnson [1]: The Path to Power (published 1982)
  - LBJ, Vol 1 (L) (Box P21)
    Typed draft of LBJ Vol 1 and galley of Vol 1.
  - Power Broker. LBJ Vol 1. (L) (Box P22)
  - LBJ, Vol 1 (Box N) (Box P23)
    Typescript draft (or drafts) of LBJ, Vol 1. Galleys of LBJ, Vol 1
  - File cabinet 3.1 (1 of 2 boxes). LBJ. Label reads: Path to Power: LCRA; SC 1: Bios: Clark, Ed; Corcoran. (original drawer labels for FC 3 are in this box at front). (File cabinet 3 was the one that was jammed; Alan broke the lock and Bob scanned drawers. He decided to keep drawer 3, which had LBJ material he wanted.) (Box P39)
    37 folders. Bulk of the files concern the LCRA (Lower Colorado River Authority), circa late 1930s-early 1940s. Rest relate to campaigns of 1938-44, though there may be connections. The content includes annotated photocopies of articles, correspondence, memos, etc. from the LBJ library and elsewhere, with Caro's typed notes and impressions from his reading of various sources. The only interviews I saw were a few handwritten notes in the last folder. A central focus here seems to be on A.J. Wirtz, who was Undersecy of the interior and later General Counsel for the LCRA. One document that might be particularly interesting is a 1975 memoir of the LCRA's history, from a Mary Rather who worked for Wirtz & LBJ (in LCRA Morrison folder). there is a small notebook in the box, but it seems mostly personal.
  - File cabinet 3.1 (2 of 2 boxes) (Box P40)
    29 folders. Most relate to SCI (Senate Campaign I), 1941. Original campaign ephemera in the "Senate Campaign I" folder. Content same as above (photocopies, notes, typed summaries). Set of biographical folders on Edward A. Clark (Austin attorney & LBJ supporter), including a 1983 interview and write-up on Clark by Jordan Cowman. Set of biolgraphical files on Thomas Corcoran. Various folders are about Caro and the books: a folder "Vol. II, Ina's comments" have her perspective on sources; photocopies of articles about Caro (1980s); "Path: Reviews" includes book reviews for that and Power Broker'; and "Nice letters" includes some letters to Caro.There is one audiocassette tape; "March 23, 1983. Posh Oltorf, Continuation of George Brown interview"
  - Path to Power (Box P50)
    8 copies of Vol 1's "uncorrected proof."
  - Box from back room: MSS outlines for LBJ Vol 1 (Leland Olds) and Desks of the Senate. Also: file folders for NYA and Sorensen OH were written on the box, but not noted in original manifest. (Box P57)
    Principal thing in this box are 7 folders with Ina's notes, photocopied documents, etc. on National Youth Administration (NYA), which seems to relate to African-American employment here. There is also a folder, notepads, and loose pages of Caro outlines and chapter sketches for LBJ volumes; largely disorganized but relates mostly to Leland Olds, building a relationship with Richard Russell as path to Presidency, and Senate history. Also in box:7 books (3 Texas almanacs, 1 on Allan Shivers, 3 on what appear to be topics of more personal interest (one has 2 snapshots including one of Caro, 1980s?). A bound copy of Theodore Sorenson oral history from JFK Library. And there are also various personal things floating around here: offer for a film of the Power Broker, speaking engagements, account statement(s), insurance offer, articles and references about Caro that he seemed to set aside for publicity use, etc.
- Series V. The Years of Lyndon Johnson [2]: Means of Ascent (published 1990)
  - File cabinet 3.2 (1 of 2 boxes). LBJ. Label reads: Means of Ascent: SC II. (original drawer label in box P39) (Box P41)
    48 folders. All on Senate Campaign II (SC II). Includes drafts, outlines, research notes, photocopies. Folder on Salas that includes Caro's notes/extracts from the manuscript (maanuscript is in box 101). The folder "SC II Summary" includes summaries/extracts from Caro's interviews, though I didn't see any full interview write-ups here.
  - File cabinet 3.2 (2 of 2 boxes) (Box P42)
    35 folders. Mostly or all continues with SC II. Folders on George Parr, Coke Stevenson (photograph, copy of oral history, etc) and material that relates to Caro's NYT article, with Ina's comments. Folders on Tom Clark. No interviews or original material jumps out. Mostly photocopies and typed notes.
  - Loose Vol II LBJ MSS and 2 LBJ binders. From lower right shelf under binders from side room lower cabinet. This is material Bob identified on the spot for Larry to pull out and take. (Box P60)
    Typescript draft(s) of LBJ Vol 2, heavily edited/annotated. Two binders of photocopies of news clippings: 1949-53, 1954-57. the 2nd volume has what seems to be an index to the 2 binders.
  - Home Sweet Home trunk 1 (1 of 3 boxes). Means of Ascent, etc (Box P63)
    Heavily edited and annotated drafts and outlines for LBJ, Vol 2. In the middle of the box are many notepads and loose sheets that are difficult to pin down. Most seem to be related to LBJ Vol 2, but might also relate to Vol. 1. A few notes refer to Moses/Power Broker, but not substantial. A few of the sheets include lists of his target interviewees and a record of how many words a day he wrote during a particular period. There might be some interview notes in there. But generally no source documents here.
- Series VI. The Years of Lyndon Johnson [3]: Master of the Senate (published 2002)
  - File cabinet 4.1. (1 of 2 boxes). LBJ. Label reads: Vol. III Outlines, Senate: '49-'58, Senate Political Files (original file cabinet 4 drawer labels are in this box). (1 of 2) (Box P45)
    73 folders. The first many folders hold outlines for various parts of Vol 3 (Senate years). Also folders with Ina's comments on the volume, Andy Hughes's legal review, and the original letters from Senate Historian Ritchie with interesting comments on the volume. Many of these outlines seem to relate to the 1956 civil rights bill. The rest of the folders are subject-oriented with the usual mix of photocopies of news articles and documents from the LBJ library and elsewhere, Caro's typed summaries of his sources (no interviews jumped out), and outlines. Principal topics seem to be Senate history in general, LBJ's first year in Senate (1949), his 1955 heart attack, and much on the Senate and LBJ in 1956.
  - File cabinet 4.1. (2 of 2 boxes) LBJ. Vol III. (Box P46)
    37 folders continues from above. Research files on Senate politics and biographies of select figures. Sources are mostly LBJ Library, but some significant material from Thomas Corcoran papers at Library of Congress and various oral histories from Southern senators (folder indicates summaries are from Ina). Photocopies (notably of George Reedy and and office memos, and some chapters of unpublished Corcoran MSS), Caro summaries of sources.
  - File cabinet 4.2. (1 of 2 boxes) LBJ. Vol III. Label reads: Sen: '49 - Longoria, Olds; Eisenhower & Johnson; Senators' Bios; Oilmenl Library: review requests; Sen: CR-Bernstein; Master: Special Letters. (original drawer label in box P45) (Box P47)